Guide to the Peter Gardner collection, 1959-1966 MS 779
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Peter Gardner collection
1959-1966
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Gardner, Peter
MS 779
61.9 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0779aip_001 (61.9 GB)
This collection consists of digitized wav and mp3 files, along with jpeg images of the original 2-track audio reels created by Peter Gardner.
Biographical / Historical
Born in 1933, Peter Gardner grew up in Cleveland. He attended Haverford College in Pennsyylvania receiving a Bachelor's degree in Psychology and a Master's degree in Music.
From the late 1950s to the early 1960s, he toured the United States and Europe with his then wife, Isabelle Ganz, under the stage name The Gardners. They recorded two albums, entitled "Peter and Isabel; The Gardners" (1962) and "Folksongs Far and Near" (1963).
The couple eventually settled in Houston in 1962, when Peter Gardner became the Director of Adult Activities at the Jewish Community Center. In this role, he organized a seasonal folk music series. Starting in 1965 and ending in 1966, he hosted the KRBE show "The Sampler" from his home at 716 W. Alabama in Houston.
During this time period, he opened up his home to pickin' parties where folk singers Guy Clark and Townes Van Zandt met. The Jewish Community Center folk series influenced a generation of Houston folk musicians with performances by John A. Lomax, Jr., Lightnin' Hopkins, and Mance Lipscomb.
In 1969, Peter Gardner moved to the Boston area. He became a practicing psychotherapist, as well as a consultant. He lived in the area until he passed in 1993.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of digitized wav and mp3 files, along with jpeg images of the original 2-track audio reels created by Peter Gardner. This audio mainly covers live recordings at the Jewish Community Center and live tapings of the radio show "The Sampler."
Conditions Governing Access
Request access to this digital material (stored on Fondren Library's nearline / non-public server) by contacting Woodson Research Center staff at woodson@rice.edu. Please use the Identifier number in your request. This material is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Matthew Gardner in September 2018.
Index Terms
Subjects
Music; Folk music -- Texas -- Houston; Jews and Jewish life
- Series I: Concerts and other recordings
  - Accent on Sound - Ron and Nama, Gene and Francesca, The Gardners, 1959-05-08; Gardner_Tape_1
    Scope and Contents
    These digitized audio files consist of one master copy wav, one access copy mp3, and jpg images of the reel, box, and any ephemera.
    Contents include: Skip Weshner's show recorded at The Village Gate in Greenwich Village, NY. Audio is poor. In order of performance, Ron and Nama, Gene and Francesca, The Gardners
  - Accent on Sound - Theodore Bikel and Geula Gill, 1959-05-13; Gardner_Tape_2
    Contents include: Skip Weshner's show recorded at The Village Gate in Greenwich Village, NY. Audio is poor. In order of performance, Theodore Bikel and Geula Gill. The reel lists a separate group of performers who were on the same show, but not in the recorded section.
  - Les Claypool Show - Mike Janus, Josh White, Bob Gibson, The Gardners, 1959-10-10; Gardner_Tape_4
    Contents include: Mike Janus; Tape b contains: Josh White via album, Bob Gibson at the Ash Grove live previous recording, The Gardners live at the Ash Grove "Cockleshells," "Morena"
  - Accent on Sound - Will Holt, Gene and Francesca, 1959; Gardner_Tape_43
    Contents include: Skip Weshner's show features Will Holt - "Raspberries, Strawberries," and three other songs. Gene and Francesca sing the final song. Audio quality is poor.
  - The Theodore Bikel Show - The Cumberland Three, Judy Bronk, The Gardners, The Song Spinners, 1960-08-11; Gardner_Tape_5
    Contents include: Taped at Gerde's Folk City, WBAI-FM. In order of performance, The Cumberland Three, Judy Bronk, Theodore Bikel, The Gardners - "Morena," "Tumbalalaika," "The Keeper" At this point, Isabel performs as Mira.; The Song Spinners: Logan English, Stella Graham, Marty Lauren, Jack Kennon
  - Accent on Sound - Ramblin' Jack Elliott, Peter La Farge, The Clancy Brothers, Tommy Makem, Billy Faier, Brother John Sellers, John Stauber, 1960; Gardner_Tape_44
    Contents include: Skip Weshner's show at 1 Sheridan Square features in order Ramblin' Jack Elliott; Peter La Farge; Oscar [?]; The Clancy Brothers and Tommy Makem; Billy Faier; Brother John Sellers; Billy Faier; John Stauber. Audio quality is poor.
  - Accent on Sound - Jacques Manahem, Anita Sheer, Oranim Zabar, 1962; Gardner_Tape_3
    Contents include: Skip Weshner's show recorded at Cafe Kasit in Tel Aviv, Israel. In order of performance, Jacques Manahem, Anita Sheer and Jacques Manahem, Oranim Zabar Troupe: Dov Seltzer, Geula Gill, Michael Kagan
  - Peter Childs, The Gardners [?], 1962; Gardner_Tape_47
    Contents include: Peter Childs - dobro instrumental, "Titanic"; Arthur Hodges and company -"Brazos," Peter Childs - "Lay on That Job Too Long," "Sixteen Tons," Instrumental, "The 219 Train"; Arthur Hodges - "Blue Mountain," 12-string guitar; b-recording: casual recording of The Gardners [?] and others
  - Jewish Community Center Concert - Frank Davis and Kay Oslin, 1963-02-09; Gardner_Tape_13
    Contents include: Frank Davis and Kay Oslin - solos and duets, mostly Frank Davis
  - Peter Childs and Knob Lick Upper 10,000, 1963-08; Gardner_Tape_33
    Contents include: Jam session, contains conversations. The trio performed in Houston at the Music Hall on 1963-08-17. Based on accents the location of the recording is in the southern U.S.
  - Peter Childs and Knob Lick Upper 10,000, 1963-08; Gardner_Tape_45
    Contents include: Casual recordings of Peter Childs and Knob Lick Upper 10,000
  - Jewish Community Center Concert - The Flatlanders, reel 1 and 2, 1963-09-22; Gardner_Tape_6, Gardner_Tape_7
    Contents include: Pete Rose, Gene Bryant, Paul Butts - bluegrass band
  - Jewish Community Center Concert - Isabel Gardner, Mary Helen Kuhne, Abbie Lipschutz, Howie Porper, reel 1 and 2, 1963-10-20; Gardner_Tape_8, Gardner_Tape_9
    Contents include: Isabel Gardner later Isabelle Ganz, Mary Helen Kuhne, Abbie Lipschutz, and Howie Porper performing Jewish and Israeli folk music.
  - Jewish Community Center Concert - Roger Abrahams, Sara Wiggins, Reel 1 and 2, 1963-11-10; Gardner_Tape_10, Gardner_Tape_11
    Contents include: Reel 1: Roger Abrahams taught English at the University of Texas. Reel 2: Contents include: side a: same as above, side b: classical music event first part, later - is a practice session, others speaking in background, a man performing
  - Jewish Community Center Concert - Alex Martin and The Gospel Mellowtones, 1963-12-08; Gardner_Tape_12
    Contents include: In order of performance - Alex Martin, The Gospel Mellowtones from the Bella Vista Baptist Church in Houston, Alex Martin, The Gospel Mellowtones
  - Isabelle Ganz and Peter Gardner, 1963; Gardner_Tape_38
    Contents include: Practice tape of Isabelle Ganz and Peter Gardner "Morena," Stories read aloud recorded from the radio, Isabelle Ganz, Peter Gardner, and others practicing "Serenade" by Hadyn, other song unknown; various radio content
  - Jewish Community Center Concert - John A. Lomax, Jr., John Q. Anderson, Jim McConnell, 1964-03-01; Gardner_Tape_14
    Contents include: John A. Lomax, Jr., John Q. Anderson, professor of English at Texas A and M University, Jim McConnell. This performance is a song swap format.
  - Jewish Community Center Concert - Music for Strings, 1964-04-19; Gardner_Tape_15
    Contents include: Handel - Overture to "Theodora" for Strings and Klavier; Mozart - Concerto #3 for Cembalo in E Flat Major K. 107 from a Clavier Sonata by Johann Christian Bach; Geminaiani - Concerto Grosso in B Flat Major, Op. 3, No. 5 for Strings and Klavier; Telemann - Concerto for Violin and Violincello in E Major; Locatelli - Concerto Grosso for String Orchestra and Klavier in E. Major, Op. 1, no. 6. Musicians include: Violins: Fredell Lack Eichhorn, Juri Jelagin, Richard Collins, Doris Musgrave; Violas: Wayne Crouse, Violetta Moncada; Violincello: Shirley Trepel; Contrabass: Philip Edley; Cembalo and Musical Director: Albert Hirsh
  - Jewish Community Center Concert - The American Caravan Singers - Ed Badeaux, Peter Gardner, Jim McConnell, Howard Porper, Ben Ramey, reel 1 and 2 [?], 1964-10-15; Gardner_Tape_16, Gardner_Tape_32
    Contents include: The American Caravan Singers doing songs from an unreleased recording. Singers and players include: Ed Badeaux, Peter Gardner, Jim McConnell, and Howard "Howie" Porper. Reel 2 seems to be the second part of this concert, although the box is not labeled clearly.
  - Jewish Community Center [?] - Jim Womack and John A. Lomax, Jr., reel 1, 2, and 3, 1964; Gardner_Tape_48, Gardner_Tape_49, Gardner_Tape_50
    Contents include: Jim Womack and John A. Lomax, Jr. song swap
  - Frank Davis and Kay Oslin, 1964; Gardner_Tape_55
    Contents include: Casual recording of Frank Davis and Kay Oslin
  - Jewish Community Center Concert - Segle Fry, 1965-01-28; Gardner_Tape_17
    Contents include: Segle Fry from Dallas, TX.
  - Jewish Community Center Concert [?] - John A. Lomax, Jr. and Los Galleros, 1965-02-25; Gardner_Tape_54
    Contents include: John A. Lomax, Jr. and Los Galleros
  - Jewish Community Center Concert - Frank Davis and Kay Oslin, reel 1 and 2, 1965-03-25; Gardner_Tape_18, Gardner_Tape_19
    Contents include: Reel 1: Frank Davis and Kay Oslin singing duets and solos. Jim Gunn is on bass. Tracks include: Tape a: "Big Fat Woman," "John Hardy," "Sand Mountain," "Old Paint," "The Cuckoo," "Bill Campbell," "Jean Harlow," "Sun"; Tape b: "Every night," "Devil and the Farmer's Wife," "Long John," "Pretty Polly," "When I Was a Cowboy," "In the Pines". Reel 2: Contents include: Frank Davis and Kay Oslin singing duets and solos. Jim Gunn is on bass. Tracks include: "Jole Blon," "God Bless the Child," "My Home's Across the Smokey Mountains," "The Brazos," "Rattlesnack Mountain," "Big Fat Woman," "Irene"
  - Casual recording - Carolyn Terry, Peter Childs, Frank Davis, Sara Wiggins, 1965-04-12; Gardner_Tape_20
    Contents include: "Little Maggie" - Carolyn Terry, Peter Childs; "Motherless Child" - Frank Davis, Peter Childs, Sara Wiggins, Carolyn Terry; "Long John Green" - John A. Lomax, Jr. with others repeating lines in unison
  - Jewish Community Center Concert - Houston Folklore Society, reel 1 and 2, 1965-04-29; Gardner_Tape_21, Gardner_Tape_22
    Contents include: Reel 1: John A. Lomax, Jr. describes the society, its history, and is the master of ceremonies. Davy Jones - "East Virginia," "Bobby Campbell"; Rick Kelly and Bob Stetson - "The Road to Freedom," "I'm Going Home"; Mrs. Joe Liday [?] - "Battle of New Orleans," "Lass from the Low Country"; Mike Rickard [?] and George Lyons [?] - "Mr. Tambourine Man," "Call Me Lonesome"; Carolyn Terry - "Shake Sugaree," "The Demon Lover"; Tom Reeve [?] - "Freight Train," "900 Miles"; Brian Evans and Dave Singleton - "River Is Wide," Peter, Paul and Mary instrumental; John Rogers - "Come My Son". Reel 2: Contents include: John A. Lomax, Jr. is the master of ceremonies. Hank Slaughter - "Tell Old Bill," "Goodbye Rosalita"; Ken Boggs - Instrumental, "Empty Pocket Blues"; Linda Miller - "Donna Donna," "Five Hundred Miles," "Two Brothers"; Joe Johnson, Bill Taylor, and Michael White - "Steel Guitar Rag," "Beaumont Rag," Instrumental; Sharon Steenberg - "Bittersweet," "Remember the Alamo"; Pete Wheeler - "Poor Little Turtledove," "Little Margaret"; George Lyons [?] - "All I Really Want to Do," "She Loves You," "Blues in My Bottle," "Motorcycle Song"; Recording abruptly ends.
  - Party at Don Snell's - The Moonshiners - Bill Northcutt, Bill Bonner, Bill Bailey, Doc Hamilton, Robby Shipley, Gary White, reel 1 and 2, 1965-05-15; Gardner_Tape_23, Gardner_Tape_24
    Contents include: Reel 1: The Moonshiners - "Darling Nelly Gray," "Greenland Fisheries," "Rattler's Pup," "Let Those Brown Eyes Smile at Me," "Orange Blossom Special," "The Girl I Left in Sunny Tennessee," Instrumental, "The Little White Washed Chimney," "We'll Meet Again Sweetheart," Instrumental, Instrumental, "A Flower Blooming in the Wildwood," "Banks of the Ohio," "Homestead on the Farm," 'Uncle Pen," "Speedy John Hardy," "The Blue Ridge Mountain Blues," "It Ain't Gonna Rain No More," "Roll in My Sweet Baby's Arms," Instrumental, "The Salty Dog Blues," "Sinking of the Rueben James," "Goodbye, Mary Dear". Reel 2: Contents include: The Moonshiners - "Old Salty Dog Blues," "Old Joe Clark," "Let Those Brown Eyes Smile at Me," Instrumental, "The Blue Moon of Kentucky," "Mountain Dew," "Home on the Hill"
  - Jewish Community Center Concert - Dave Parker, reel 1 and 2, 1965-06-20; Gardner_Tape_26, Gardner_Tape_27
    Contents include: Dave Parker, classical guitarist
  - Jewish Community Center Concert - Ballet Folklorico, Sarah Wiggins, Jim McConnell, Peter Childs, 1965-06; Gardner_Tape_36
    Contents include: "Albur de Amor" (Ranchera), "Desden" (Peru's Waltz), "El Quelite," "Caminante Del Mayab" (Yucatan), "Adios" (Peru). Performers: Rosario Aragon, Guadalupe Jimenez, Pedro Munoz, Horacio Bigurra, Fernando Rojas, Emilio Parades; Sarah Wiggins and Jim McConnell - "In Terry Town"; Peter Childs and Jim McConnell - "Nine Pound Hammer (Roll on Buddy)," "Darby Ram," "Stagolee," "St. Louis Blues"
  - Jewish Community Center Concert - Paul Johnson, Kathy Rote, Carolyn Terry, Gary White, 1965-10-07; Gardner_Tape_25
    Contents include: Paul Johnson - "Coal Town," "Diamond," "Lesson Too Late," "Winkin and Blinkin," "Atom," "Trig," "Silvie," "Soul Song," "Oh My Lady"; Kathy Rote - "The Wild Rippling Waters," "Early, Early in the Spring," "A Dog Named Blue," "Duncan and Brady," "Two Little Boys," "Dear Companion," "Cotton Mill Girls," "I've Got Mine," "Me and My Uncle"; Carolyn Terry - "Hootenanny Granny," "Blues My Naughty Sweetie Gives to Me," "I Love My Darling, Oh," "Young Girl Cut Down in Her Prime," "The Unquiet Grave," "Sand Mountain Blues," "Shake Sugaree," "One Grain of Sand," "Inside a Lion"; Gary White - "The Royal Canal," "Standing on the Outside of Your Shelter," "Man of Constant Sorrow," "Hannah McGlue [?]," "Snake Cure," "Winnsboro Cotton Mill Blues," "Little Margaret," "Hungry Hash House," "High Flying Bird." Reel abruptly ends.
  - Jewish Community Center Concert - Jim McConnell, Amy Goodenough, 1965-12-02; Gardner_Tape_28
    Contents include: Amy Goodenough - "Circle Around the Sun," "Fragments"; Jim McConnell - "Other Side of Jordan," "Rude and Ramblin' Man"; Amy Goodenough - "Pretty Polly," "Grey Cock," with Paul Johnson "Winken and Blinken and Nod"; Jim McConnell - "I Don't Reckon That'll Happen Again," "Ballad of Otto Wood," "Deep River Blues,"; Amy Goodenough - "New Shoes Blues"; Jim McConnell - "Quince Brigada," with Uda McConnell "Sunny Side of Life"; Amy Goodenough - "Lucky Joe," "A Living Song"; Jim McConnell - "Tom Dooley," "Stay Away from the Girls"
  - Jewish Community Center Concert - Jim McConnell, Amy Goodenough, Guy Clark, Peter Childs; Guy Clark, Sarah Wiggins, Carolyn Terry home recordings, 1965-12-02; Gardner_Tape_29
    Contents include: Side a: Amy Goodenough - "Cotton Mill Girls"; Jim McConnell and Amy Goodenough- "Delia's Gone," "He's in the Jailhouse Now"; Amy Goodenough - "The Dove"; Jim McConell - "When God Dips His Love"; Amy Goodenough - "A Blacksmith Courted Me," "Seven Sons in Yarrow"; Not from Jewish Community Center Concert, but from "The Sampler" - Guy Clark - "Pans of Biscuits"; Peter Childs - instrumental "Buckdancer's Choice"; Side b: Not from concert, home recordings - Guy Clark and Sarah Wiggins [?] - "Come All You Fair and Tender Ladies," "When First Unto This Country," "Where I'm Bound," "Keep Your Hands Off Her"; Carolyn Terry - "Little Maggie"; Guy Clark - "Frankie and Johnny," "Black Jack David"
  - Pete Wheeler [?], Paul Johnson, Townes Van Zandt, Amy Goodenough, 1965; Gardner_Tape_34
    Contents include: Performance by unknown artist - Pete Wheeler [?] - "Sylvie," "Oh My Lady" [?]; Paul Johnson - "The Talking Atomic Blues" aka "Old Man Atom," a section of the song repeats, "Prelude et Impromptu" again song ends and then repeats the last section, "The Last Think on My Mind," "In the Hills of Shiloh," "Angel on My Shoulder"; incomplete - Townes Van Zandt - "The Talking KKK Blues," Paul Johnson - "Heather on the Hill," makes a reference to Townes Van Zandt "Give Me the Wine"; Amy Goodenough and Paul Johnson - "Song for Canada" incomplete; Paul Johnson; Paul Johnson - "Green Grow the Lilacs"
  - Peter Childs, Peter Gardner, Shel Silverstein, Leadbelly, 1965; Gardner_Tape_37
    Contents include: Peter Childs and Peter Gardner - "Brazos"; Shel Silverstein - "Folk Singers Blues," "Beans Taste Fine," "It Does Not Pay to be Hip," "Blue Eyes," "Bananas," "Liz," "You're Always Welcome at Our House," "25 Minutes to Go"; Leadbelly all tracks from Sings Folk Songs, Folkways Records FA 2488.
  - Jim McConnell, Peter Childs, Peter Gardner, Sarah Wiggins, Gary Wright, 1965; Gardner_Tape_39
    Contents include: Casual recording: Jim McConnell and Peter Childs on banjo - "I Saw the Light"; Instrumental; Jim McConnell, Peter Childs, Peter Gardner - "Somewhere Listening," "Aunt Rhody," "Two Little Boys," Gary White [?], Sarah Wiggins [?], and others "That's What You Get for Lovin' Me," "Don't Thnk Twice, It's All Right," "Follow the Drinking Gourd," "I Got a Home in That Rock," "So Cane" [?]
  - Peter Childs and Frank Davis, 1965; Gardner_Tape_41
    Contents include: Casual recording of Peter Childs and Frank Davis
  - Peter Childs, 1965; Gardner_Tape_46
    Contents include: Casual recordings of Peter Childs
  - Peter Childs, 1965; Gardner_Tape_51
    Contents include: "San Francisco Bay Blues," "Stack O' Lee," "The Last Thing on My Mind," "My Name is Morgan," "It's the Same the Whole World Over," "Winnsboro Cotton Mill Blues," "Gary Gould's Daughter," "I Ride an Old Paint," "What Have They Done to the Rain," "Go Tell It on the Mountain," "Buffalo Skinners," "Buck Dancer's Choice"
  - Peter Childs, 1965; Gardner_Tape_52
    Contents include: "Get up and Go," "You're Gonna Need Somebody on Your Bond," "The Old Fish Song," "Foggy Foggy Dew," "It Takes a Worried Man"
  - Jam sessions - Guy Clark, Sarah Wiggins [?], 1965; Gardner_Tape_42
    Contents include: Extensive jam sessions from casual recordings. Various singers and players. Guy Clark - "Hello Bill" sings part of song; Guy Clark and Sarah Wiggins [?] - "Shake Sugaree," "Rambler, Gambler"
  - Jewish Community Center Concert [?] - Unidentified female singer, 1965; Gardner_Tape_53
    Contents include: Woman singer, does a duet with Peter Gardner, perhaps woman is Sharon Steenberger; b-side: bluegrass instrumental
  - Jewish Community Center - Sarah Wiggins and Guy Clark, 1966-01-27; Gardner_Tape_35
    Contents include: Sarah Wiggins - "Pretty Mary," "No More Cane on the Brazos," "Lolly Too Dum," "Shake Sugaree," "Take a Look at Me" [?], "The Coming of the Roads"; Guy Clark - "San Francisco Bay Blues," "Tying a Knot in the Devil's Tail," "Zebra Dung," "One Too Many Mornings," "Tell Old Bill," "Talking Blues," "Frankie and Johnny"; Sarah Wiggins and Guy Clark - "Pack Up Your Sorrows," "Pretty Boy Floyd," "In the Early Morning Rain," "Keep Your Hands Off"; Guy Clark and Sarah Wiggins - "John" [?], "Im Going Back to Where I Come From," "Rambling Boy," Guy Clark - 1st time for concert at the venue and Sarah's second, "Memphis, Tennessee"
  - Jerry Jeff Walker and Townes Van Zandt, pre-dates 1966-02-24; Gardner_Tape_40
    Contents include: Jerry Jeff Walker - "Mountains I Have Known"; Townes Van Zandt - "Big Country Blues," "The Talking KKK Blues"; Jerry Jeff Walker - "Is It Tears or Is It Rain," "Gertrude," "New Orleans Talking Construction Blues," "Cast Off That Shell," "The Ballad of the Hulk," "Speak Now, The Dead Can't Hear You" [?], "Free Bird in a Cage" [?], "Hansel and Gretel," Townes Van Zandt and Jerry Jeff Walker on harmonica - "Tater Pie" (improvisational), "Trouble in Mind," "Cocaine Done Killed My Baby" (improvisational verses)
  - Jewish Community Center Concert - Jerry Jeff Walker, Townes Van Zandt, 1966-02-24; Gardner_Tape_30
    Contents include: Jerry Jeff Walker - "Yesterdays Begin Today" [?], Learning to Play Guitar song, "Is It Tears or Is It Rain," "It's the Same Damn Thing," "New Orleans Talking Construction Blues," "Gertrude," "Cast Off That Shell," "The Ballad of the Hulk," "Ramblin Scramblin," "Gypsy Songman" "Roads of My Mind," "Drifting Way of Life"; Townes Van Zandt - "Big Country Blues," "The Talking KKK Blues," "To My Friend That's Gone Along His Way" [?] - original song, "The Ballad of Ira Hayes," "For All Free Men to Go" [?] - original song, "Laying Down Here Thinking" [?] - original song, "Sixteen Summers, Fifteen Falls," "Cocaine in My Brain," "Badly Mistreated Blues" [?] - original song, "Waiting Around to Die," "Talking Karate Blues," "I'll Be Here in the Morning" - song written for wife that morning lyrics are different; Townes Van Zandt and Jerry Jeff Walker on harmonica - "Trouble in Mind," "This Train Is Bound for Glory"
  - Jewish Community Center Concert - John A. Lomax, Jr., Bob Gaston, Susan Spaw, 1966-03-31; Gardner_Tape_31
    Contents include: Performers in order: Bob Gaston, John A. Lomax, Jr., Susan Spaw, John A. Lomax, Jr.
- Series II: KRBE - "The Sampler"
  - The Sampler - Guy Clark, Frank Davis, Peter Childs, 1965-04-12; Gardner_Sampler_1
    Contents include: Recorded live at 716 W. Alabama at Peter Gardner's home. Guy Clark - "Pride of Petrovar," "You Don't Know"; Frank Davis - "Big Fat Woman," "East Virginia"; Peter Childs - "San Francisco Bay Blues," "Candy Man"; Guy Clark - "Baby Ain't No Lie"; Frank Davis - "Man Who Wouldn't Hoe Corn"; Peter Childs - "Easy Rider"
  - The Sampler - Ed Badeaux, Peter Childs, 1965-04-16; Gardner_Sampler_2
    Contents include: Recorded live at 716 W. Alabama at Peter Gardner's home. Contents include: Peter Childs on banjo and Ed Badeaux guitar - "Earl's breakdown"; Ed Badeaux and Peter Childs on dobro - "Jimmy Brown"; Ed Badeaux - "Knot in the Devil's Tail"; Peter Childs - "Battle Ship of Maine," "Risselty-Rossety"; Ed Badeaux - "Guitar Playing Talking Blues"; Peter Childs - "You're Gonna Need Somebody on Your Bond"; Ed Badeaux - "Kitty Clyde"; Instrumental closing
  - The Sampler - Peter Childs, Carolyn Terry, Guy Clark, Sarah Wiggins, 1965-04-20; Gardner_Sampler_3
    Contents include: Recorded live at 716 W. Alabama at Peter Gardner's home. Peter Childs - instrumental - Travis picking; Carolyn Terry - "Shake Sugaree"; Carolyn Terry and Peter Childs - "Little Maggie"; Guy Clark and Sarah Wiggins recently began working together - "Fair and Tender Ladies," "Johnson Boys"; Peter Childs - "My Name Is Morgan," "Under the Double Eagle"; Carolyn Terry - "Moonshiner"; Peter Childs - "Who's Gonna Shoe," closing
  - The Sampler - Jim McConnell, Pete Wheeler, Peter Childs, 1965-04-26; 1965-05-05; Gardner_Sampler_4
    Contents include: Recorded live at 716 W. Alabama at Peter Gardner's home. Instrumental opening; Jim McConnell - "Other Side of Jordan," "Woody Knows Nothing"; Pete Wheeler - "Billy Grimes," "Bonny Lass of Fyvie"; Peter Childs - "Buffalo Skinners," "Talking Dust Bowl"; Jim McConnell - "When God Dips His Love in My Heart"; Pete Wheeler - "In Dublin City"; Peter Childs and Jim McConnell - instrumental closing
  - The Sampler - Davy Jones, Sharon Steenberger, Guy Clark, 1965-05-03; Gardner_Sampler_5